All right. So, we have talked about
行。所以，我们已经谈过了
regular neural networks,
常规神经网络，
fully connected neural networks,
完全连接的神经网络，
we have talked about convolutional neural networks
我们已经讨论过卷积神经网络
that work with images,
使用图像，
we have talked about Reinforcement,
我们谈到过强化，
Deeper Reinforcement Learning,
更深入的强化学习，
where we plug in a neural network
我们插入神经网络的地方
into a Reinforcement Learning Algorithm,
到强化学习算法，
when a system has to not only
当一个系统不仅要
perceive the world but also act in it,
感知世界，但也在其中行动，
and collect a reward.
并收取奖励。
And today we will talk about,
今天我们来谈谈，
perhaps the least understood
也许是最不了解的
but the most exciting neural network out there,
但那里最激动人心的神经网络，
flavor of neural networks, is Recurrent Neural Networks.
神经网络的味道，是递归神经网络。
But first, for administrative stuff,
但首先，对于行政人员，
there’s a website. I don’t know if you heard,
有一个网站。我不知道你是否听说过，
cars.mit.edu,
cars.mit.edu，
where you should create an account, if you’re a registered student,
如果您是注册学生，您应该在哪里创建一个帐户，
that’s one of the requirements.
这是要求之一。
You need to have an account
你需要一个帐户
if you want to get credit for this,
如果你想得到这个，
you need to submit code
你需要提交代码
for DeepTrafficJS, and DeepTeslaJS,
对于DeepTrafficJS和DeepTeslaJS，
and for DeepTraffic,
对于DeepTraffic，
you have to have a neural network that drives faster than 65mph.
你必须有一个驱动速度超过65英里每小时的神经网络。
If you need help to achieve that speed
如果您需要帮助来达到这个速度
please e-mail us.
请发电子邮件给我们。
We can give you some hints.
我们可以给你一些提示。
For those of you who are old school SNL fans,
对于那些是老派SNL粉丝的人，
there’s the Deep Thoughts section now,
现在有深度思考部分，
in the profile page,
在个人资料页面中，
where we encourage you to talk about
我们鼓励你谈谈的地方
the kinds of things that you tried in DeepTraffic
您在DeepTraffic中尝试过的各种事物
or any of the other
或任何其他的
DeepTesla or any of the work you've done
DeepTesla或您完成的任何工作
as part of this class for DeepLearning.
作为DeepLearning课程的一部分。
Okay,
好的，
we have talked about
我们已经谈过了
the Vanilla Neural Networks on the left.
左边的香草神经网络。
The Vanilla Neural Network
香草神经网络
is the one where it's computing
是它计算的那个
is approximating a function that maps from one input
近似于从一个输入映射的函数
to one output.
到一个输出。
An example is mapping images
一个例子是映射图像
to the number that is shown in the image.
到图像中显示的数字。
For ImageNet
对于ImageNet
is mapping an image
正在映射图像
to what's the object in the image.
什么是图像中的对象。
It can be anything.
它可以是任何东西。
In fact,
事实上，
Convolutional Neural Networks can operate on audio,
卷积神经网络可以对音频进行操作，
you can give it a chunk of audio, a five second audio clip,
你可以给它一大块音频，一个五秒音频剪辑，
that still counts as one input
仍然算作一个输入
because it’s fixed-size.
因为它是固定大小的。
As long as the size of the input is fixed,
只要输入的大小是固定的，
that's one chunk of input
这是一大块投入
and as long as you have ground truth
只要你有基本的事实
that maps that chunk of input to some output
将该输入块映射到某个输出
ground truth,
事实上，
that’s the Vanilla Neural Network.
那就是香草神经网络。
Whether there's a fully connected neural network
是否有完全连接的神经网络
or convolutional neural network.
或卷积神经网络。
Today we’ll talk about the amazing,
今天我们将谈论惊人的，
the mysterious Recurrent Neural Networks.
神秘的回归神经网络。
They compute functions
他们计算功能
from one to many,
从一个到多个，
from many to one,
从多到一，
from many to many.
从很多到很多。
Also bidirectional.
也是双向的。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
They take its input sequences,
他们接受输入序列，
time series,
时间序列，
audio,
音频，
video,
视频，
whenever there's a sequence of data,
只要有一系列数据，
and that temporal dynamics
和时间动态
that connects the data
连接数据
is more important than the spatial
比空间更重要
content of each individual frame.
每个框架的内容。
So, whenever there's a lot of information
所以，每当有很多信息时
being conveyed in a sequence,
按顺序传达，
in a temporal change
在时间变化
of whatever that type of data is,
无论那种类型的数据是什么，
that's when you want to use Recurrent Neural Networks
那是你想要使用回归神经网络的时候
like speech,
喜欢说话，
natural language,
自然语言，
audio
音频
and the power of this
和这个的力量
is that for many of them,
对于他们中的许多人来说，
for a Recurrent Neural Network,
对于递归神经网络，
where they really shine,
他们真正发光的地方，
is when the size of the input is variable,
当输入的大小是可变的，
so you don’t have a fixed chunk of data
所以你没有固定的数据块
that you're putting in is variable input.
你输入的是可变输入。
And the same goes for the output,
输出也一样，
so you can give it a sequence of speech,
所以你可以给它一系列的演讲，
several seconds of speech
几秒钟的演讲
and then the output is
然后输出是
a single label of whether the speaker is male or female.
扬声器是男性还是女性的单一标签。
That’s many to one.
这是多对一的。
You can also do
你也可以这样做
many to many.
很多很多。
Translation.
翻译。
You can have natural language
你可以拥有自然语言
put into the network
投入网络
in Spanish
在西班牙语中
and the output is in English.
输出是英文的。
Machine translation.
机器翻译。
That's many to many.
那是多对多的。
And that many to many doesn't have to be
并且许多人不必这样做
mapped directly
直接映射
into same sized sequences.
分成相同大小的序列。
For video, the sequence size might be the same
对于视频，序列大小可能相同
you're labeling every single frame, you put in
你放入了每一帧的标签
a five second clip
一个五秒钟的剪辑
of somebody playing basketball
打篮球的人
and you can label every single frame
你可以标记每一帧
counting the number of people in every single frame.
计算每一帧中的人数。
That's many to many
那是多对多的
when the size of the input and the size of the output is the same
当输入的大小和输出的大小相同时
Yes, question?
是的，问题？
The question was,
问题是，
are there are any models where there's feedback from output and input?
是否有任何型号的输出和输入有反馈？
That's exactly what Recurrent Neural Networks are.
这正是回归神经网络的意义所在。
It produces output,
它产生输出，
and it copies that output
并复制该输出
and loops it back in.
并将其循环回来。
That's almost the definition of a Recurrent Neural Network.
这几乎就是回归神经网络的定义。
There's a loop in there that produces the output
那里有一个产生输出的循环
and also takes that output as input once again.
并再次将该输出作为输入。
There's also many to many where the sequences don't align.
还有许多序列不对齐的地方。
Like machine translation,
像机器翻译一样
the size of the output sequence
输出序列的大小
might be  totally different than the input sequence.
可能与输入序列完全不同。
We will look on a lot of cool applications;
我们将介绍很多很酷的应用程序;
you can start a song,
你可以开一首歌
learn the audio of a particular song
学习特定歌曲的音频
have the Recurrent Neural Network
有回归神经网络
to continue that song after a certain period of time.
在一段时间后继续播放这首歌。
So it can learn to generate sequences
因此它可以学习生成序列
of audio, of natural language, of video.
音频，自然语言，视频。
Okay.
好的。
I know I promised not many equations,
我知道我答应的方程式不多，
but this is
但这是
so beautifully simple
非常简单
that we have to cover backpropagation.
我们必须涵盖反向传播。
It's also the thing
这也是事情
that, if you're a little bit lazy
那，如果你有点懒
and you go to the internet
你去互联网
and start using the basic tutorials of TensorFlow,
并开始使用TensorFlow的基本教程，
you ignore how backpropagation work.
你忽略了反向传播的工作原理。
At you peril.
在你身上危险
You kind of assume it just works.
你认为它只是有效。
I give it some inputs, some outputs,
我给它一些输入，一些输出，
and it's like Lego pieces I can assemble them
它就像我可以装配它们的乐高积木
like you might have done with DeepTraffic
就像你可能已经完成了DeepTraffic
A bunch of layers put in together
一堆层放在一起
and then just press Train.
然后按下火车。
backpropagation is the mechanism
反向传播是机制
that neural networks currently--
那个神经网络目前 -
The best mechanism we know of that is used for training.
我们所知道的最佳机制用于培训。
So you need to understand
所以你需要了解
the simple power of backpropagation,
反向传播的简单力量，
but also the dangers.
但也有危险。
Summary,
摘要，
I put on the top of the slide, there's an input
我放在幻灯片的顶部，有一个输入
for the network that's an image,
对于一个图像的网络，
there's a bunch of neurons,
有一堆神经元，
all with differentiable
一切都差别化
smooth activation functions on each neuron,
每个神经元上的平滑激活功能，
and then,
然后，
as you pass through those activation functions,
当你通过这些激活函数时，
take in an input, pass it through
接受输入，传递它
this net of differentiable compute nodes,
这个可区分的计算节点网，
you produce an output.
你产生了一个输出。
In that output
在那个输出中
you also have a ground truth,
你也有一个基本的事实，
the correct, the truth
正确的，真相
that you hope
你希望
or you expect the network to produce.
或者你期望网络生产。
And you can look at the differences between
你可以看看它们之间的差异
what the network actually produced
网络实际产生了什么
and what you hoped it would produce,
你希望它会产生什么，
and that's an error.
这是一个错误。
And then you backward propagate that error,
然后你向后传播那个错误，
punishing or rewarding
惩罚或奖励
the parameters of the network that resulted in that output
导致该输出的网络参数
Let's start with a really simple example.
让我们从一个非常简单的例子开始吧。
There's a function
有一个功能
that takes its input
需要它的输入
up on top,
在顶部，
three variables, X, Y and Z.
三个变量，X，Y和Z.
The function does two things:
该功能做两件事：
it adds X and Y
它增加了X和Y.
and then it multiplies
然后它成倍增加
that sum by Z.
Z的总和。
And then we can formulate that as a circuit,
然后我们可以将其表述为电路，
circuit of gates,
门电路，
where there's a Plus gate,
哪里有一个加号门，
and a Multiplication gate.
和乘法门。
Let's take some inputs,
我们来一些投入，
shown in blue.
以蓝色显示。
Let's say it's X is negative two,
让我们说它的X是负二，
Y is five and Z is negative four.
Y为5，Z为负4。
And let's do a forward pass
让我们做一个前锋传球
through the circuit
通过电路
to produce the output.
产生输出。
Negative two plus five equals three
负二加五等于三
q is that intermediate value,
q是那个中间值，
three.
三。
This is so simple,
这很简单，
and so important to understand
了解如此重要
that I just want to take my time for this
我只是想花时间来做这件事
because everything else about neural networks just builds on these concepts
因为神经网络的其他一切都建立在这些概念之上
The add gate produces q,
添加门产生q，
in this case, is three,
在这种情况下，是三，
and three times negative four is twelve.
三次负四是十二。
That's the output.
这是输出。
The output of the circuit of this network,
该网络电路的输出，
if you think of it as such,
如果你这样想，
is negative twelve.
是负十二。
The forward pass is shown in blue
前向传球以蓝色显示
the backward pass will be shown in red
向后传球将以红色显示
in a second here
在这里的第二个
What we want to do,
我们想做什么
what would make us happy,
是什么让我们开心，
what would make f happy
什么让快乐
is for the output to be as high possible.
是为了尽可能高的输出。
Negative twelve, so-so, it could be better.
负十二，一般，它可能会更好。
How do we teach it
我们如何教它
How do we adjust X, Y and Z,
我们如何调整X，Y和Z，
to ensure it produces a higher f
确保它产生更高的f
makes f happier.
让我更快乐。
Let's start backward,
让我们开始向后，
The backward pass.
向后传球。
We'll make the gradient on the output one,
我们将在输出上设置渐变，
meaning we want this to increase.
意思是我们希望这个增加。
We want f to increase.
我们希望f增加。
That's how we\hencode our happiness.
这就是我们如何编码我们的幸福。
We want it to go up by one.
我们希望它一个接一个。
In order to then propagate
然后再传播
that fact that we want
我们想要的那个事实
the f to go up by one,
f上升一，
we have to look at
我们要看一下
the gradient on each one of the gates.
每个门上的梯度。
And what's a gradient?
什么是梯度？
It's a
它是
partial derivative
偏导数
with respect to its inputs.
就其投入而言。
The partial derivative of the output of the gate
门输出的偏导数
with respect to its inputs,
就其投入而言，
if you don't know what that means,
如果你不知道这意味着什么，
is just
只是
how much does the output change
输出变化多少
when I change the inputs a little bit.
当我稍微改变输入时。
What is the slope of that change if I increase X
如果我增加X，那个变化的斜率是多少
for the first function of addition,
对于第一个添加功能，
f of X, Y equals X plus Y.
X的Y，Y等于X加Y.
If I increase X by a little bit,
如果我稍微增加X，
what happens to f?
怎么回事？
If I increase Y by a little bit,
如果我稍微增加Y，f会发生什么？
Taking a partial derivative of those
采取那些的偏导数
with respect to X and Y
关于X和Y.
you just get a slope of one
你得到一个斜坡
When you increase X,
当你增加X时，
f increases linearly.
f线性增加。
Same with Y.
与Y相同
Multiplication is a little trickier.
乘法有点棘手。
When you increase X,
当你增加X时，
f increases by Y.
f增加Y.
Do the partial derivative of f with respect to X is Y,
f相对于X的偏导数是Y，
the partial derivative of f with respect to Y is X.
f相对于Y的偏导数是X.
If you think about it, what happens is
如果你考虑一下，会发生什么
the gradients, when you change X,
渐变，当你改变X时，
the gradient of change
变化的梯度
doesn't care about X.
不关心X.
It cares about Y.
它关心Y.
It's flipped.
它被翻转了。
So we can backpropagate that one,
所以我们可以反过来传播那一个，
the indication of what makes X happy backward.
是什么让X快乐落后的迹象。
And that's done by
这完成了
computing the local gradient.
计算局部梯度。
For q,
对于q，
the partial derivative of f with respect to q,
f的相对于q的偏导数，
that intermediate value,
那中间值，
that gradient would be negative four.
那个梯度将是负四。
It will take the value of Z
它将取Z的值
as I said it's the Multiplication gate,
正如我所说的那样是乘法门，
and assign it to the gradient.
并将其分配给渐变。
And the same for
同样的
the partial derivative of f with respect to Z,
f相对于Z的偏导数，
it will assign that to q.
它会将其分配给q。
The value of the forward pass on the q.
q的正向传递值。
There's a three
有三个
and a negative four on the forward pass in blue
蓝色前进传球中的负四
and that's flipped.
那就是翻了。
Negative four and three
负四和三
on the backward pass.
在落后的传球。
That's the gradient.
那是渐变。
And then we continue in the same exact process.
然后我们继续进行相同的过程。
But wait.
可是等等。
What makes all of this work,
是什么让所有这些工作，
is the Chain Rule.
是连锁规则。
It's magical.
这太神奇了。
What it allows us to do
它允许我们做什么
is to compute the gradient,
是计算梯度，
the gradien of f with respect to the inputs X, Y, Z.
相对于输入X，Y，Z的f的梯度。
We don't need to construct
我们不需要构建
the giant function that is
这个巨大的功能
the partial derivative of f with respect to X, Y and Z
f的相对于X，Y和Z的偏导数
analytically.
解析。
We can do it step by step
我们可以一步一步做到这一点
backpropagating the gradients.
反向传播渐变。
We can multiply the gradients together
我们可以将梯度相乘
as opposed to doing the partial derivative
而不是做偏导数
of f with respect to X.
f相对于X.
We have just the intermediate,
我们只有中级，
the local gradient
局部渐变
of f with respect to q, and of q with respect to X,
f相对于q，q相对于X，
and multiply them together.
并将它们相乘。
So, Instead of computing
所以，而不是计算
gradient of that
那个渐变
giant function X plus Y times Z,
巨功能X加Y倍Z，
in this case is not that giant,
在这种情况下不是那么巨大，
but it gets pretty giant with neural networks,
但它与神经网络相比变得非常巨大，
we just go step by step.
我们一步一步走。
Look at the first function,
看看第一个函数，
simple addition, q equals X plus Y,
简单加法，q等于X加Y，
and the second function, multiplication,
和第二个函数，乘法，
f equals q times Z.
f等于q乘以Z.
The gradient on X and Y,
X和Y上的渐变，
the partial derivative
偏导数
of f with respect to X and Y
f对X和Y的关系
is computed by multiplying
通过乘以计算
the gradient on the output, negative four,
输出上的梯度，负四，
times the gradient on the inputs,
乘以输入的渐变，
which as we talked about,
正如我们所谈到的，
when the operation is addition,
当操作添加时，
that's just one.
那只是一个。
It's negative four times one.
这是负四倍。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Let's interpret those numbers.
让我们解释这些数字。
You now have gradients on X, Y and Z
您现在在X，Y和Z上有渐变
the partial derivatives of F with respect to X, Y, Z.
F的偏导数相对于X，Y，Z。
That means,
那意味着，
for X and Y is negative four, for Z is three.
对于X和Y是负四，因为Z是三。
That means, in order to make f happy,
这意味着，为了让快乐，
we have to decrease
我们必须减少
the inputs that have a negative gradient
具有负梯度的输入
and increase the inputs that have a positive gradient.
并增加具有正梯度的输入。
The negatives ones are X and Y,
负面的是X和Y，
the positive is Z.
积极的是Z.
Hopefully, I don't say
希望，我不说
the word “Beautiful” too many times in this presentation
在这个演讲中，“美丽”这个词太多次了
this is very simple. Beautifully simple.
这很简单。非常简单。
Because this gradient is a local worker,
因为这个梯度是本地工人，
it propagates for you;
它为你传播;
it has no knowledge of the broader
它不了解更广泛的
happiness of f.
f的快乐
It computes the greater between the output and the input.
它计算输出和输入之间的较大值。
And it can propagate this gradient
它可以传播这个渐变
based on,
基于，
in this case f,
在这种情况下f，
a gradient of one but also the error.
一个渐变，但也错误。
Instead of one we can have on the output the error
而不是我们可以在输出上有错误
as the measure of happiness.
作为幸福的衡量标准。
And then we can propagate that error backwards.
然后我们可以向后传播该错误。
These gates are important because we can break down
这些门是重要的，因为我们可以打破
almost every operation we can think of
几乎我们能想到的每一项操作
that we work within neural networks
我们在神经网络中工作
into one or several gates like these.
进入这样的一个或几个门。
The most popular are three,
最受欢迎的是三个，
which is addition, multiplication
这是加法，乘法
and the Max operation.
和Max操作。
For addition,
另外，
the process is
这个过程是
you take a forward pass through the network,
你通过网络前进，
so we have a value on every single gate,
所以我们每个门都有一个价值，
and then you take the backward pass.
然后你采取向后传球。
And through the backward pass you compute those gradients.
通过向后传递，您可以计算出这些渐变。
For an add gate,
对于添加门，
you equally distribute the gradients
你平均分配渐变
on the output to the input,
在输出到输入，
when the gradient on the output is negative four,
当输出的梯度为负四时，
you equally distribute it tonegative four.
你平均分配它的四种情感。
And you ignore the forward pass value.
你忽略了前向传递值。
That three is ignored when you backpropagate it.
当你反向传播时，这三个被忽略了。
On the Multiply gate,
在乘法门上，
it's trickier.
这比较棘手。
You switch the forward pass values,
你切换正向传递值，
if you look at f, that's a Multiply gate,
如果你看f，那是一个乘法门，
the forward pass values are switched
切换正向传递值
and multiplied by the value of the gradient in the output.
并乘以输出中的渐变值。
If it's confusing, go through the slides slowly.
如果它令人困惑，请慢慢浏览幻灯片。
It'll make a lot more sense.
它会更有意义。
Hopefully.
希望。
One more gate. There's the Max gate,
还有一个门。有Max门，
which takes the inputs
它接受输入
and produces as output
并作为输出产生
the value that is larger.
更大的价值。
When computing the gradient of the Max gate,
在计算Max门的梯度时，
it distributes the gradient
它分配渐变
similarly to the Add gate, but to only one, to only one  of the inputs;
类似于添加门，但只有一个，只有一个输入;
the largest one.
最大的一个。
unlike the Add gate, pays attention to the input
与添加门不同，注意输入
the input values on the forward pass.
正向传递的输入值。
All right.
行。
Lots of numbers but the whole point here is,
很多数字，但这里的重点是，
it's really simple;
它真的很简单;
a neural network is just a simple collection of these gates.
神经网络只是这些门的简单集合。
You take a forward pass,
你前往传球，
you calculate some kind of function
你计算某种功能
in the end, the gradient in the very end,
最后，最后的渐变，
and you propagate that back.
然后你传播回来。
Usually, for neural networks, that's an Error function.
通常，对于神经网络，这是一个错误函数。
A Loss function, Objective function,
损失函数，目标函数，
a Cost function. All the same word.
成本函数。所有相同的词。
That's the Sigmoid function there
这就是那里的Sigmoid功能
When you have three weights
当你有三个重量
W zero, W one, W two
W零，W一，W两
and X, two inputs, X0, X1,
和X，两个输入，X0，X1，
that's going to be the Sigmoid function.
这将是Sigmoid功能。
That's how you compute the output
这就是你计算输出的方式
of the neuron.
神经元
But then you can decompose that neuron
但是你可以分解那个神经元
you can separate it all into
你可以将它全部分开
just a set of gates like this
只是这样一套门
Addition, multiplication,
加法，乘法，
there's an exponential in there and division
在那里和分裂有一个指数
but all very similar.
但都非常相似。
And you repeat the exact same process.
你重复完全相同的过程。
there's five inputs,
有五个输入，
there's three weights
有三个重量
and two inputs. X zero, X one.
和两个输入。 X零，X一。
You take a forward pass through this circuit,
你通过这个赛道前进，
in this case again,
在这种情况下，再次，
you want it to increase so that the gradient of the output is one
你希望它增加，使输出的梯度为1
and you backpropagate that gradient
然后你反向传播那个渐变
of one,\hto the inputs.
一，投入。
Now in neural networks,
现在在神经网络中，
there's a bunch of parameters
有一堆参数
that you're trying through this process, modify.
您正在尝试完成此过程，请进行修改。
And you don't get to modify the inputs
而且你无法修改输入
You get to modify the weights along the way,
你可以沿途修改重量，
and the biases.
和偏见。
The inputs are fixed,
输入是固定的，
the outputs are fixed,
输出是固定的，
the outputs that you hope
你希望的产出
the network will produce.
网络将产生。
What you're modifying is the weights.
你要修改的是权重。
So I get to try to adjust those weights
所以我试着调整那些重量
in the direction of the gradient.
在梯度的方向。
That's the task of backpropagation.\h
这是反向传播的任务。
The main way that neural networks learn.
神经网络学习的主要方式。
As we update the weights and the biases
当我们更新权重和偏见时
to decrease the loss function.
减少损失功能。
The lower the loss function the better.
损失函数越低越好。
In this case, you have
在这种情况下，你有
three inputs on the top left.
左上角有三个输入。
A simple network, three inputs.
一个简单的网络，三个输入。
Three weights on each of the inputs.
每个输入上有三个权重。
There's a bias on the node,
节点上存在偏差，
b and produces an output
b并产生输出
a, and that little symbol is indicating a Sigmoid function.
a，该小符号表示Sigmoid功能。
And the loss
和损失
is computed as Y minus A squared,
计算为Y减去A平方，
divided by two,
除以2，
where Y is the ground truth,
Y是基本事实，
the output that you want the network to produce.
您希望网络生成的输出。
And that loss function is backpropagating
而且这种损失函数正在反向传播
in exactly the same way that we described before.
与我们之前描述的方式完全相同。
The subtasks
子任务
involved in this update of weights and biases
参与权重和偏见的更新
is that the forward pass computes
是前进传球计算
the network output at every neuron,
每个神经元的网络输出，
and finally, the output layer,
最后，输出层，
computes the error, the difference between a and b,
计算错误，a和b之间的差异，
and then
然后
backward propagates the gradients.
向后传播渐变。
Instead of one on the output,
而不是输出上的一个，
it will be the error on the output and you backpropagated.
这将是输出上的错误，你反向传播。
And then, once you know the gradient,
然后，一旦你知道了渐变，
you adjust the weights and the biases
你调整权重和偏见
in the direction of the gradient.
在梯度的方向。
Actually, the opposite of the direction of the gradient,
实际上，与梯度方向相反，
because you want the loss to decrease.
因为你希望损失减少。
And the amount by which you make that adjustment
以及进行调整的金额
is called the Learning Rate.
被称为学习率。
The learning rate can be the same across the entire network
整个网络的学习率可以相同
or can be individual through every weight.
或者可以通过每个重量来个体化。
And the process
而这个过程
of adjusting the weights and biases
调整重量和偏差
is just optimization.
只是优化。
Learning is an Optimization problem.
学习是一个优化问题。
You have an objective function, and you're trying to minimize it.
你有一个客观的功能，你正试图最小化它。
And your variables are the parameters, the weights and biases.
而你的变量是参数，权重和偏差。
Neural networks just happen to have
神经网络恰巧有
tens, hundreds of thousands, millions
数十万，数十万，数百万
of those parameters.
那些参数。
So the function that you're trying to minimize is highly non-linear.
因此，您尝试最小化的功能是高度非线性的。
But it boils down to something like this, you have
但它归结为类似的东西，你有
two weights, two plots-- or actually one weight
两个重量，两个地块 - 或实际上一个重量
and as you adjust it, the cost
当你调整它，成本
you adjust in such a way that minimizes the output cost.
您可以通过最小化输出成本的方式进行调整。
And there's a bunch of optimization methods for doing this.
还有一堆优化方法可以做到这一点。
this is a convex function,
这是一个凸函数，
You can find the local minimum.
你可以找到当地的最低要求。
If you know about these kinds of terminologies,
如果您了解这些术语，
the local minimum is the same as the global minimum,
当地最小值与全局最小值相同，
it's not a weirdly hilly terrain
这不是一个奇怪的丘陵地形
where you can get stuck in.
你可以陷入困境的地方。
Your goal is to get to the bottom of this thing
你的目标是深入了解这件事
and if it's really complex terrain,
如果这是非常复杂的地形，
it will be hard to get to the bottom of it.
很难找到它的底部。
This general approach is gradient descent,
这种一般方法是梯度下降，
and there's a lot of different ways to do a gradient descent.
并且有许多不同的方法来进行梯度下降。
Various ways of adding randomness into the process,
将随机性添加到流程中的各种方法，
so you don't get stuck into the weird
所以你不要陷入奇怪的境地
crevices of the terrain.
地形的裂缝。
But it's messy.
但它很乱。
You have to be really careful.
你必须非常小心。
This is the part you have to be aware of,
这是你必须要注意的部分，
when you design a network for DeepTraffic
为DeepTraffic设计网络时
and nothing is happening
没有任何事情发生
this might be what's happening:
这可能是正在发生的事情：
vanishing gradients
消失的渐变
or exploding gradients.
或爆炸渐变。
When the partial derivatives
当偏导数
are small, so you take the Sigmoid function,
很小，所以你采取Sigmoid函数，
the most popular
最受欢迎
for a while, activation function,
一段时间，激活功能，
the derivative is zero at the tails.
尾部的导数为零。
When the input to
当输入到
the Sigmoid functions is really high or really low,
Sigmoid函数非常高或非常低，
that derivative is going to be zero.
该衍生品将为零。
Gradient tells on how much I want to adjust the weights.
渐变告诉我要调整多少权重。
The gradient might be zero,
渐变可能为零，
and so you backpropagate that zero,
所以你反向传播零，
a very low number,
数量很少，
and it gets less and less
它变得越来越少
as you backpropagate
当你反向传播
and so the result is that
结果就是这样
you think you don't need to adjust the weights at all.
你认为你根本不需要调整重量。
And when a large fraction of the network
而当网络的很大一部分
weights don't need to be adjusted,
重量不需要调整，
they don't adjust the weights.
他们不调整重量。
And you are not doing any learning
你没有做任何学习
So the learning is slow.
所以学习很慢。
There are some fixes to this,
这有一些修复，
there are different types of functions.
有不同类型的功能。
There's a piece,
有一块，
the ReLUs function which is the most popular activation function.
ReLUs功能是最受欢迎的激活功能。
But again,
但是，
if the neurons are initialized poorly,
如果神经元初始化不良，
this function might not fire.
这个功能可能不会触发。
it might be zero gradient
它可能是零梯度
for the entire data set.
对于整个数据集。
Nothing that you produce as input,
没有你作为输入产生，
you run all your thousands of images of cats,
你运行所有成千上万的猫图像，
and none of them fire at all.
而且他们都没有开枪。
That's the danger here.
这就是危险。
So you have to pick
所以你必须选择
both the optimization engine,
两个优化引擎，
the solver that you use
你使用的解算器
and the activation functions carefully.
并且激活功能小心。
You can't just plug and play like they're Lego's
你不能只是像Lego那样即插即用
You have to be aware of the function.
你必须要知道这个功能。
SGD, Stochastic Gradient Descent,
SGD，随机梯度下降，
that's the Vanilla optimization algorithm
这是Vanilla优化算法
for gradient descent.
用于梯度下降。
For optimizing the loss function over the gradients
用于优化梯度上的损耗函数
And what's visualized here is,
这里可视化的是，
again, if you have done any numerical optimization,
再次，如果你做了任何数值优化，
and non-linear optimization,
和非线性优化，
there's the famous saddle point,
有着名的马鞍点，
that's tricky for these algorithms to deal with.
对于这些算法来说，这很棘手。
What happens is, it's easy for them to oscillate,
会发生什么，它们很容易振荡，
get stuck in that saddle and oscillating back and forth
卡在那个马鞍上来回摆动
as opposed to what they want to do which is
而不是他们想做的事情
go down into--
进入 -
You get so happy that you found this
你很高兴找到了这个
low point
低点
that you forget there's a much lower point.
你忘了那里有一个低得多的点。
So you get stuck with the gradient.
所以你会陷入渐变。
The momentum of the gradient
渐变的势头
keeps rocking it back and forth without you going
在你不去的情况下来回摇摆
to a much greater global minimum.
全球最低限度。
And there's a lot of clever ways to solving that,
并且有很多聪明的方法来解决这个问题，
the Atom optimizer is one of those.
Atom优化器就是其中之一。
But in this case, as long as the gradients don't vanish
但在这种情况下，只要渐变不消失
SGD, the Stochastic Gradient Descent,
SGD，随机梯度下降，
one of these algorithms will get you there
其中一种算法可以帮助你
It might take a little while, but it will get you there
可能需要一段时间，但它会让你到那里
Yes, question.
是的，问题。
The question was,
问题是，
you're dealing with a function that is not convex,
你正在处理一个非凸的函数，
how do we ensure anything about
我们如何确保任何事情
converging to anything that's
收敛到任何东西
reasonably good,
相当不错，
the local optimum converges to--
局部最优收敛于 -
The answer is, you can't.
答案是，你做不到。
This isn't only a non-linear function
这不仅是非线性函数
it's a highly non-function
这是一个高度无功能的
The power and the beauty of neural networks
神经网络的力量和美丽
is that it can represent these arbitrarily complex functions.
是它可以代表这些任意复杂的功能。
It's incredible.
这太不可思议了。
And it can learn these functions from data
它可以从数据中学习这些功能
But the reason people are referring to neural networks training as art
但人们将神经网络训练称为艺术的原因
is you're trying to play with parameters
你正试图玩参数吗？
that don't get stuck in these local optimal.
不要陷入这些局部最优。
For stupid reasons and for clever reasons.
出于愚蠢的原因和聪明的原因。
Yes, question.
是的，问题。
The Question continues on the same thread.
该问题继续在同一个主题上。
The thing is, we're dealing with functions
问题是，我们正在处理功能
where we don't know what the global optimal is.
我们不知道全局最优的是什么。
That's the crocs of it.
这就是它的鳄鱼。
Everything we talked about,
我们谈论的一切，
interpreting text,
解释文字，
interpreting video,
解读视频，
even driving.
甚至开车。
What's the optimal for driving?
什么是驾驶的最佳选择？
Never crashing?
永远不会崩溃？
It sounds easy to say that,
听起来很容易，
you actually have to formulate the world
你实际上必须制定世界
under which it defines all of those things and it becomes a really
在它下面定义所有这些东西，它变成了一个真正的东西
non-linear objective function
非线性目标函数
for which you don't know what the optimal is.
你不知道最佳的是什么。
That's why you keep trying
这就是你继续努力的原因
and get impressed every time it gets better.
并且每次变好都会给人留下深刻的印象。
It is essentially the process.
这基本上就是这个过程。
And you can also compare,
你也可以比较，
you can compare with human-level performance.
你可以与人类的表现进行比较。
For ImageNet,
对于ImageNet，
who can tell the difference between cats and dogs,
谁能分辨出猫狗之间的区别，
and top five categories,
和前五个类别，
96% of the time accuracy,
96％的时间准确度，
and then you get impressed when
然后你会留下深刻的印象
a machine can do better than that.
一台机器可以做得更好。
But you don't know what the best is.
但你不知道什么是最好的。
These videos can be watched for hours,
这些视频可以观看几个小时，
I won't play it until I explain this slide.
在我解释这张幻灯片之前我不会播放它。
Let's pause to reflect on backpropagation
让我们暂停以反思反向传播
before I go on to Recurrent Neural Networks. Yes, question.
在我继续回归神经网络之前。是的，问题。
In this practical manner, how can you tell when
以这种实际的方式，你怎么知道什么时候
you're actually creating a net whether you're
无论你是谁，你实际上是在创造一个网络
facing the management gradient problem
面对管理梯度问题
or you need to change your optimizer
或者您需要更改优化程序
or you've reached a local minimum?
或者你达到了当地的最低标准？
The question was,
问题是，
how do you practically know
你怎么知道的
when you hit the vanishing gradient problem?
当你遇到消失的梯度问题？
The vanishing gradient could be--
消失的梯度可能是 -
The derivative being zero on the gradient,
梯度上的导数为零，
happens when the activation is exploding,
当激活爆炸时发生，
like really high values
喜欢真正的高价值
and really low values.
而且价值非常低。
To really high values is easy.
真正的高价值很容易。
Your network has just gone crazy.
你的网络刚刚疯了。
It produces very large values.
它产生非常大的值。
And you can fix a lot of those things by just capping the activations.
你可以通过限制激活来解决很多这些问题。
The values being really low,
价值真的很低，
resulting in a vanishing gradient, are really hard to detect
导致渐变的消失，真的很难被发现
There's a lot of research in trying to figure out
试图弄清楚有很多研究
how to detect these things.
如何检测这些东西。
If you're not careful, often times
如果你经常不小心的话
you can find that,
你可以找到，
and this isn't hard to do,
这不难做到
we're like 40 or 50 percent of the network,
我们就像40％或50％的网络，
of the neurons,
神经元，
are dead.
是死的。
We will call it, for ReLU,
我们称之为ReLU，
they're dead ReLU
他们已经死了ReLU
They're not firing at all.
他们根本没有开火。
How do you detect that?
你怎么发现的？
That's part of learning
这是学习的一部分
If they never fire you can detect that
如果他们从未开火，你可以发现它
by running it through the entire training set.
通过在整个训练集中运行它。
There are a lot of tricks. But that's the problem.
有很多技巧。但那就是问题所在。
You try to learn
你试着学习
and then you look at the loss function
然后你看一下损失函数
and it's not
而事实并非如此
converging to anything reasonable.
融合到任何合理的东西。
They are going all over the place, or just converging very slowly.
他们到处都是，或者只是非常慢地融合。
And that's an indication that something is wrong
这表明出现了问题
That something could be the loss function is bad,
那个东西可能是损失函数很糟糕，
that something could be you already found the optimal,
你可能已经找到了最佳的东西，
or that something could be the vanishing gradient.
或者某种东西可能是消失的梯度。
And again, that's why it's an art.
再次，这就是为什么它是一门艺术。
Certainly,
当然，
at least some fraction of the neurons needs to be firing.
至少有一部分神经元需要射击。
Otherwise, initialization is really poorly done.
否则，初始化真的很糟糕。
Okay, to reflect on the
好的，要反思一下
simplicity of backpropagation
简单的反向传播
and the power of it,
和它的力量，
this kind of step of
这种步骤
backpropagating the loss function to the gradients locally,
将损失函数反向传播到局部的梯度，
is the way neural networks learn.
是神经网络学习的方式。
It's really the only way
这是唯一的方法
that we have effectively been able to
我们已经有效地做到了
to train a neural network
训练神经网络
network to learn a function.
网络学习功能。
To adjusting the weights and biases,
要调整重量和偏差，
the huge number of weights and biases, the parameters
大量的权重和偏差，参数
It's just through this optimization.
这只是通过这种优化。
It's backpropagating the error,
它反向传播错误，
where you have the supervised ground truth.
你有监督的基本事实。
the question is
问题是
whether this process, of fitting,
是否适合这个过程，
adjusting the parameters
调整参数
of a highly non-linear function to minimize a single objective,
高度非线性函数，以最小化单个目标，
is the way you achieve intelligence.
是你实现智慧的方式。
Human-level intelligence.
人类智慧。
That's something to think about.
这是值得思考的问题。
You have to think about, for driving purposes,
出于驾驶目的，你必须考虑一下
what is the limitation of this approach?
这种方法的局限性是什么？
What's not happening?
什么没发生？
The neural network designed, the architecture
神经网络设计，架构
is not being adjusted.
没有调整。
any of the edges, the layers, nothing is being evolved
任何边缘，层，没有任何东西进化
There are other optimization approaches
还有其他优化方法
that I think are more
我认为更多
interesting and inspiring than effective.
有趣和鼓舞人心而不是有效。
For example, this is
例如，这是
using soft cubes to--
使用软立方体 -
This is falling out of the field
这已经失控了
of evolutionary robotics.
进化机器人学。
Where you evolve
你进化的地方
the dynamics of a robot
机器人的动力学
using genetic algorithms
使用遗传算法
and that's
那是
These robots have been taught to,
这些机器人已被教导，
in simulation, obviously,
在模拟中，显然，
to walk and to swim.
走路和游泳。
That one is swimming.
那是游泳。
The nice thing here is that dynamics
这里的好处是动态
that highly non- linear space as well,
非常非线性的空间，
that controls the dynamics of this weird shaped robot
控制这个奇怪形状的机器人的动态
with a lot of degrees of freedom,
有很多自由度，
it's the same kind of thing as the\hneural network.
它与神经网络是一回事。
In fact, people have applied generic algorithms,
事实上，人们已经应用了通用算法，
ant colony optimization, all kinds of sort of nature inspire algorithms
蚁群优化，各种自然激发算法
for automatizing the weights and the biases
用于自动化权重和偏差
but they don't seem to currently work that well.
但他们目前似乎并没有这么好。
It's a cool idea to\hbe using
这是一个很酷的想法
nature-type evolutionary algorithms to evolve
自然型进化算法的演化
something that's already nature inspired which is neural networks.
已经被大自然启发的东西是神经网络。
But, something to think about
但是，有待考虑的事情
the backpropagation, while really simple
反向传播，虽然很简单
it's kind of dumb and the question is whether
这有点愚蠢，问题是，是否
general intelligence reasoning can be achieved with this process.
通过这个过程可以实现一般情报推理。
All right, Recurrent Neural Networks,
好的，回归神经网络，
on the left there's an input X
在左边有一个输入X.
with weights on the input, U,
在输入上有权重，U，
there's a hidden state,
有一个隐藏的状态，
hidden layer S,
隐藏层S，
with weights on
有重量
the edge connecting
边缘连接
the hidden states to each other
相互隐藏的状态
and then more weights, V, the on the output O.
然后更多权重，V，输出O.
It's a really simple network, there's inputs,
这是一个非常简单的网络，有输入，
there's hidden states,
有隐藏的状态，
the memory of this network
这个网络的记忆
and there's outputs.
并且有输出。
But the fact that there's
但事实就是这样
this loop
这个循环
where the hidden states are connected to each other
隐藏状态彼此连接的地方
means that as opposed to producing a single input,
意味着与产生单一输入相反，
the network takes arbitrary numbers of inputs,
网络采用任意数量的输入，
it just keeps taking X, one at a time
它只是一次一个地拿着X.
and produces a sequence of Xs
并产生一系列Xs
through time.
通过时间。
Depending on
取决于
the duration of the sequence you're interested in,
您感兴趣的序列的持续时间，
you can think of this network
你可以想到这个网络
in its unrolled state.
处于展开状态。
You can unroll this neural network
您可以展开此神经网络
where the inputs are in the bottom, Xt-1, Xt, Xt+1,
输入在底部，Xt-1，Xt，Xt + 1，
and same with the outputs,
和输出一样
Ot-1, Ot, Ot+1,
Ot-1，Ot，Ot + 1，
and it becomes like a regular neural network,
它变得像一个普通的神经网络，
unrolled some arbitrary number of times.
展开了一些任意次数。
The parameters, again,
参数，再次，
there's weights, there's\hbiases,
有重量，有偏见，
similar to CNNs,
类似于CNN，
convolutional neural networks
卷积神经网络
and just like convolutional neural networks
就像卷积神经网络一样
make certain spatial consistency assumptions,
做出一定的空间一致性假设，
the recurrent neural network assume
递归神经网络假设
temporal consistency amongst the parameters,
参数之间的时间一致性，
shares the parameters.
分享参数。
That W, that U, that V,
那个W，那个U，那个V，
is the same for every single time step.
每一个时间步都是一样的。
You're learning
你正在学习
the same parameter,
相同的参数，
no matter the duration of the sequence
无论序列的持续时间
and that allows you to
这可以让你
look at arbitrary long sequences
看看任意长序列
without having an explosion of parameters.\h
没有参数爆炸。
This process is the same exact process that's repeated
这个过程与重复的过程完全相同
base on the different variants that we talk about before,
基于我们之前谈到的不同变体，
in terms of inputs and outputs,
在投入和产出方面，
one to many, many to one, many to many.
一对多，多对一，多对多。
The backpropagation process
反向传播过程
is exactly the same as for regular neural networks.
与常规神经网络完全相同。
It's a fancy name of backpropagation through time,
这是一个时髦的反向传播的名字，
BPTT,
BPTT，
but it's just backpropagation through an unrolled
但它只是通过展开的反向传播
recurrent neural network,
递归神经网络
where the errors are on the computed on the outputs,
错误在输出上计算的位置，
the gradients are computed,
计算渐变，
backpropagated
backpropagated
and computed on the inputs,
并在输入上计算，
again, suffering for the same exact problem
再次，痛苦同样的问题
of vanishing gradients.
消失的渐变。
The problem is
问题是
that the depth of these networks can be arbitrary long
这些网络的深度可以任意长
if at any point the gradients hits
如果在任何时候梯度击中
a lower number, zero,
较低的数字，零，
becomes, that neural becomes saturated.
成为，神经变得饱和。
That gradient, let's call it saturated,
那个渐变，我们称之为饱和，
that gradient gets--
渐变得到 -
drives all the earlier layer to zero,
将所有较早的层驱动为零，
so is easy to run to a problem
所以很容易遇到问题
where you're really ignoring the majority of the sequence.
你真的忽略了大部分序列。
This is just another\hPython weight,
这只是另一个Python重量，
sudo-called weight to look at it.
sudo称为重量来看待它。
Is you have the same w,
你有同样的w，
remember you're sharing the weights
记住你正在分享权重
and all the parameters from time to time,
和所有参数，不时，
so if the weights are such
所以如果重量是这样的话
WHH,
WHH，
if the weights are such that they produce
如果重量是他们产生的
[unintelligible]
[难以理解]
they have a negative value that results
它们具有负值
in the gradient that goes to zero,
在渐变到零，
that propagates through the rest.
通过其余的传播。
That's the sudo-call for backpropagation,
这是反向传播的sudo-call，
pass to the RNN,
传递给RNN，
that WHH
WHH
propagates back.
传播回来。
You get this things
你得到这个东西
with exploding and vanishing gradients
随着爆炸和消失的渐变
for example, error surfaces for a single hidden unit RNN,
例如，单个隐藏单元RNN的错误表面，
this is visualizing the gradient,
这是可视化的渐变，
the value of the weight, the value of the bias
权重的价值，偏见的价值
and the error,
和错误，
the error could be really flat or could explode,
错误可能非常平坦或可能爆炸，
both are going to lead
两者都将领先
to you not making--
你没有 -
either making steps that are too gradual
要么采取过于渐进的步骤
or too big.
还是太大了
It's the geometric interpretation.
这是几何解释。
Okay. What other variants that we look at, a little bit?
好的。我们看一下其他什么变体？
are they [unintelligible 00:41:13]?
他们[难以理解00:41:13]？
It doesn't have to be only one way,
它不一定只有一种方式，
it can be bi-directional,
它可以是双向的，
that could be edges going forward and edges going back
这可能是前进的边缘和边缘返回
What that's needed for
需要什么
is things like
是这样的
filling in missing, whatever the data is,
填写遗失，无论数据是什么，
filling in missing elements of that data,
填写该数据的缺失元素，
whether that's images, or words, or audio.
无论是图像，文字还是音频。
Generally, as always is the case in neural network,
通常，与神经网络一样，
the deeper it goes, the better.
它越深越好。
That deep referring to the number of layers
那深层指的是层数
in a single temporal instance.
在一个时间实例中。
On the right of the slide
在幻灯片的右侧
we're stacking
我们正在堆叠
node in the temporal domain.
时域中的节点。
Each of those layers has its own set of weights,
每个层都有自己的一组权重，
its own set of biases.
它自己的偏见。
These things are awesome
这些都很棒
but they need a lot of data
但他们需要大量的数据
when you add extra layers in this way.
当您以这种方式添加额外的图层时。
The problem is, while recurrent neural network,
问题是，虽然递归神经网络，
in theory,
理论上，
is supposed to be able to learn any kind of sequence,
应该能够学习任何类型的序列，
the reality is they're not really good at remembering
现实是他们并不擅长记忆
what happened a while ago,
刚才发生的事，
the long-term dependency.
长期依赖。
Here's a silly example,
这是一个愚蠢的例子，
let's think of a story
让我们想一个故事
about Bob,
关于鲍勃，
Bob is eating an apple.
鲍勃正在吃一个苹果。
The apple part
苹果部分
is generated by the recurrent neural network.
由递归神经网络生成。
Your recurrent neural networks can learn to generate "apple"
你的反复神经网络可以学会生成“苹果”
because it's seen in a lot of sentences, with "Bob" and "eating"
因为它在很多句子中被看到，有“鲍勃”和“吃”
and it can generate the word apple.
它可以生成单词apple。
For a longer sentence, like
对于更长的句子，比如
"Bob likes apples,
“鲍勃喜欢苹果，
he's hungry and decided to have a snack,
他饿了，决定吃零食，
so now he's eating an apple",
所以现在他正在吃一个苹果“，
you have to maintain the state
你必须保持状态
that we're talking about Bob
我们在谈论鲍勃
and we're talking about apples,
我们在谈论苹果，
through several
通过几个
discreet semantic
谨慎的语义
sentences.
句子。
That kind of long-term memory
那种长期记忆
is not--
不是 -
because of different effects,
因为效果不同，
but vanishing gradients,
但消失的渐变，
it's difficult to propagate
传播很困难
the important stuff that happened a while ago
刚才发生的重要事情
in order to maintain that context
为了维持这种背景
in generating "apple",
在生成“苹果”，
or classifying\hsome concept that happened
或者对发生的一些概念进行分类
way down the line.\h
顺便说一句。
When people talk about
当人们谈论
recurrent neural networks
递归神经网络
these days, they're talking about LSTMs,
这些天，他们谈论的是LSTM，
long-short-term memory networks
长期短期记忆网络
so all the impressive results
所有令人印象深刻的结果
results on time series and audio and video
关于时间序列和音频和视频的结果
and all that, that requires LSTMs.
而这一切，都需要LSTM。
Again, vanilla RNNs
同样，香草RNN
are on top of the slide,
在幻灯片的顶部，
each cell is simple,
每个细胞都很简单，
there are some hidden units,
有一些隐藏的单位，
there's an input, and there's an output.
有一个输入，有一个输出。
Here, we used TANH as activation function,
在这里，我们使用TANH作为激活函数，
it's just another popular Sigmoid type activation function.
它只是另一种流行的Sigmoid类型激活功能。
LSTMs\hare more complicated,
LSTM更复杂，
or they look more complicated but
或者他们看起来更复杂但是
in some ways, they're more intuitive for us to understand.
在某些方面，它们对我们来说更直观。
There's a bunch of gates in each cell,
每个单元格中都有一堆门，
we'll go through those.
我们将通过这些。
In yellow are different neural network layers,
黄色是不同的神经网络层，
Sigmoid and TANH,
Sigmoid和TANH，
are just different types of activation functions.
只是不同类型的激活功能。
TANH is an activation function that
TANH是一种激活功能
squishes the input into the range of negative one to one.
将输入转移到负一对一的范围内。
Sigmoid function
Sigmoid功能
squishes it between zero and one
在零和一之间搜索它
and that serve different purposes.
这有不同的用途。
There's some pointwise operations,
有一些有意义的操作，
addition, multiplication,
加法，乘法，
and there's connections,
并且有联系，
data being passed from layer to layer,
数据从一层传递到另一层，
shown by the arrows.
箭头所示。
There's concatenation and there's a copy operation on the output
有连接，输出上有一个复制操作
We copy,
我们复制，
the output of each cell it's copied to the next cell
它被复制到下一个单元格的每个单元格的输出
and to the output.
并输出。
Let me try to make it, clarified,
让我试着澄清一下，
clarify a little bit.
澄清一点。
There's this conveyer belt
有这个输送带
going through inside of each individual cell
穿过每个单独的细胞内部
and they all have, there's really three steps in the conveyer belt.
他们都有，输送带上真的有三个台阶。
The first is,
首先是，
there is a Sigmoid function
有一个Sigmoid函数
that's responsible for deciding
那是负责决定的
what to forget and what to ignore,
忘记什么，忽略什么，
it's responsible for
它负责
taking in the input, the new input, x(t),
接受输入，新输入，x（t），
taking in the state of the previous,
采取以前的状态，
the output of the previous cell, previous time step
前一个单元格的输出，上一个时间步长
and deciding "do I want to keep that in my memory or not?"
并决定“我想把它留在我的记忆中吗？”
and "do I want to integrate
和“我想整合
the new input into my memory or not?"
我的记忆中的新输入与否？“
This allows you to
这可以让你
selective about the information which you learn.
选择性地了解您学到的信息。
For example,
例如，
there's that sentence "Bob and Alice are having lunch,
那句话“鲍勃和爱丽丝正在吃午饭，
Bob likes apples,
鲍勃喜欢苹果，
Alice like oranges,
爱丽丝喜欢橘子，
she is eating an orange".
她正在吃一个橘子“。
Bob and Alice are having lunch,
鲍勃和爱丽丝正在吃午饭，
Bob likes apples,
鲍勃喜欢苹果，
right now, if you had said you have a hidden state,
现在，如果你说你有一个隐藏的状态，
keeping track of the gender of the person we're talking about
跟踪我们所谈论的人的性别
you might say that there's both genders on the first sentence,
你可能会说第一句话有两种性别，
there's male in the second sentence,
第二句中有男性，
female in the third sentence,
女性在第三句话中，
and that way
那样
when you have to generate a sentence about who's eating what,
当你必须生成一个关于谁在吃什么的句子时，
you'll know-
你会知道 -
you keep the gender information
你保留性别信息
in order to make an accurate generation of text
为了准确生成文本
corresponding to
对应于
the proper person.
适当的人。
You have to forget certain things,
你必须忘记某些事情，
like forget that Bob existed at that moment,
就像忘了Bob那时存在的那样，
you have to forget Bob likes apples
你必须忘记鲍勃喜欢苹果
but you have to remember
但你必须记住
that Alice likes oranges
爱丽丝喜欢橘子
so you have to selectively remember and forget certain things
所以你必须有选择地记住并忘记某些事情
that's LSTM in a nutshell.
简而言之就是LSTM。
You decided what to forget, decided what to remember
你决定忘记什么，决定要记住什么
and decided what to output in that cell.
并决定在该单元格中输出什么。
Zoom in a little bit, because this is pretty cool
放大一点，因为这很酷
There's a state running through the cell,
有一个州穿过牢房，
this conveyer belt,
这个输送带，
previous state like the gender
以前的状态喜欢性别
that we're currently talking about,
我们目前正在谈论的，
that's the state that you're keeping track of
这就是你要跟踪的状态
and that's running through the cell.
那是在细胞中运行的。
Then there's three Sigmoid layers
然后有三个Sigmoid层
outputting one,
输出一个，
a number between the zero and one,
零和一之间的数字，
one when you want that information to go through
一个，当你想要的信息通过
and zero when you don't want it to go through,
当你不想让它通过时为零，
the conveyer belt that maintains the state.
保持状态的输送带。
First, Sigmoid function is,
首先，Sigmoid功能是，
we decided what to forget and what to ignore,
我们决定忘记什么，忽略什么，
that's the first one,
那是第一个，
we take the input from the previous time step,
我们从前一个时间步骤中获取输入，
the input to the network
网络的输入
on the current time step
在当前时间步骤
and decided, do I want to forget or do I want to ignore those?
并决定，我想忘记或者我想忽略那些？
Then we decided
然后我们决定了
which part of the state to update,
要更新的州的哪一部分，
what part of our memory do we have to update with this information
我们需要用这些信息更新记忆的哪一部分
and what values to insert in that update.
以及在该更新中插入的值。
Third step is, we perform the actual update
第三步，我们执行实际更新
and perform the actual forgetting,
并执行实际遗忘，
that's why you have the Sigmoid function,
这就是你有Sigmoid功能的原因，
you just multiply it,
你只是乘以它，
when is zero is forgetting,
什么时候是零是遗忘，
when is one that information passes through.
什么时候信息通过。
Finally,
最后，
we produce an output from the cell,
我们从细胞产生一个输出，
if its translation
如果它的翻译
is producing an output in the English language
用英语生成输出
where the input was in Spanish language
输入是西班牙语的
and then that same output
然后是相同的输出
it's copied to the next cell.
它被复制到下一个单元格。
What can we get done with this kind of approach?
我们可以用这种方法做些什么？
We can look at machine translation.
我们可以看一下机器翻译。
I guess what I'm trying to--
我想我正在努力 -
question.
题。
what is your representation of this state?
你对这个州的代表是什么？
Is it like a floating point
它是否像浮点
or is it like a vector
或者它就像一个矢量
or what is it, exactly?
或者究竟是什么？
The state
国家
is the activation
是激活
multiplied by the weight,
乘以重量，
it's the output of the Sigmoid or the TANH activations.
它是Sigmoid或TANH激活的输出。
There's a bunch of neurons and they're firing a number
有一堆神经元，他们正在发射一个数字
between negative one or one, or between zero and one,
在负一个或一个之间，或在零到一之间，
that whole's a state.
整个都是一个国家。
It just that calling it a state it's sort of simplifying,
只是把它称之为一种简化的状态，
but the point is that there's
但重点是，有
a bunch of numbers been constantly modified by the weights
一堆数字经常被权重修改
and the biases,
和偏见，
those numbers hold the state
这些数字持有国家
and the modification of those numbers
并修改这些数字
is controlled by the weights
由权重控制
and then once all of that is done,
一旦完成所有这一切，
the resulting output
结果输出
of the recurrent neural network
复发神经网络
it's compared to the desired output
它与所需的输出进行比较
and the errors are backpropagated to the weights.
并将错误反向传播到权重。
Hopefully, that makes sense.\h
希望这是有道理的。
So, machine translation is one popular application
因此，机器翻译是一种流行的应用程序
all of it is the same,
所有这一切都是一样的，
all of these networks that I've talked about,
我所谈到的所有这些网络，
they're really similar constructs.
他们是非常相似的结构。
You have some inputs,
你有一些投入，
whatever language that is again,
无论再说什么语言，
German maybe, I think everything is German,
德国人也许，我认为一切都是德国人，
and the output.
和输出。
The inputs are in one language,
输入是一种语言，
a set of characters
一组人物
composed a word in one language,
用一种语言组成一个单词，
there's a state being propagated
有一个国家正在传播
and once that sentence\his over,
一旦那句话结束，
you start, as opposed to collecting inputs,
你开始，而不是收集投入，
start producing outputs
开始产生产出
and you can output in the English language.
你可以用英语输出。
There's a ton of great work on machine translations.
机器翻译有很多很棒的工作。
It's what Google is supposedly using for their translator,
这是谷歌应该用于他们的翻译，
same thing.
一样。
I've show this previously
我以前说过这个
but now you all know how it works,
但现在你们都知道它是如何工作的，
same exact thing, LSTMs
同样的事情，LSTMs
generating handwritten characters,
生成手写字符，
handwriting in arbitrary styles,
任意风格的手写，
controlling the drawing,
控制绘图，
where the input is text and the output is handwriting.
输入是文本，输出是手写。
Is again, the same kind of
再次，同样的
network with some depths here,
这里有一些深度的网络，
the input is the text,
输入是文字，
the output is the control of the writing.
输出是写作的控制。
Character-level text generation,
字符级文本生成，
this is
这是
the thing that taught us about life,
告诉我们生活的东西，
the meaning of life,
生命的意义，
literary recognition and the tradition of ancient human reproduction.
文学认同与古代人类繁衍的传统。
That's again, the same process,
那是同样的过程，
input one character at the time,
当时输入一个字符，
what we see there is the encoding of the characters on the input layer,
我们看到的是输入图层上的字符编码，
there's a hidden state,
有一个隐藏的状态，
hidden layer that is keeping track of those activations,
跟踪那些激活的隐藏层，
the outputs
产出
of the activation functions and every single
激活功能和每一个
time it's outputting
它正在输出的时间
its best prediction
最好的预测
of the next character that follows.
随后的下一个字符。
Now, on a lot of these applications
现在，在很多这些应用程序上
you want to ignore the output
你想忽略输出
until the input sentence is over
直到输入句结束
and then you start\hlistening to the output,
然后你开始听输出，
but the point is that it just keeps generating text,
但关键是它只是不断生成文本，
whether is given an input or not,
无论是否给予输入，
so you producing input
所以你产生了输入
is just adding, steering
只是添加，转向
the recurrent neural network.
递归神经网络。
You can answer questions
你可以回答问题
about an image,
关于图像，
the input you get there,
你到那里的输入，
you could almost arbitrary stack things together,
你几乎可以把任意东西叠在一起，
you take an image as your input, bottom left there,
你把图像作为输入，左下角，
put it in your convolutional neural network,
把它放在卷积神经网络中，
and take the question.
并提出问题。
There's something call word embeddings,
有一些叫做嵌入字的东西，
it's to broaden
这是为了扩大
the representative meaning of the words.
这些词的代表意义。
"How many books?" is the question.
“有多少本书？”是个问题。
You want to take the word embeddings
你想要嵌入这个词
and the image
和图像
and produce
并生产
your best estimate of the answer.
你对答案的最佳估计。
For question of
对于问题
"what color is the cat?"
“猫是什么颜色的？”
it could be gray or black,
它可能是灰色或黑色，
it's the different LSTM flavors
这是不同的LSTM口味
producing that answer.
产生这个答案。
Same with counting chairs
与计数椅子相同
you can give an image of a chair
你可以给一张椅子的图像
and as the question "how many chairs are there?"
并且问题是“那里有多少把椅子？”
And it can produce an answer of "three".
它可以产生“三”的答案。
I should say this is really hard,
我应该说这真的很难，
arbitrary question
任意问题
asks an arbitrary image,
询问任意图像，
you are both interpreting--
你们都在诠释 -
you are doing natural languages processing
你正在做自然语言处理
and you're doing computer vision, all in one network.
而且你在一个网络中进行计算机视觉。
Same thing with the image capture generation,
与图像捕获生成相同，
you can detect
你可以检测到
the different objects in the scene,
场景中的不同对象，
generate those words,
生成这些词，
stitch them together in syntactically correct sentences
在语法正确的句子中将它们拼接在一起
and rearrange the sentences.
并重新排列句子。
All of those are LSTMs,
所有这些都是LSTM，
the second and the third step,
第二步和第三步，
the first is computer vision detecting the objects,
首先是检测物体的计算机视觉，
segmenting the image and
分割图像和检测物体，
that way you can generate a caption that says
这样你就可以生成一个标题
"a man is sitting in a chair with a dog in his lap".
“一个男人坐在椅子上，狗在他的腿上”。
Again, LSTMs for video.
再次，LSTMs视频。
Caption generation for video,
视频的标题生成，
the input, and every frame it's an image
输入，每一帧都是一个图像
that goes into the LSTM,
进入LSTM，
the input is an image
输入是图像
and the output is a set of characters.
输出是一组字符。
First, you load in the video,
首先，你加载视频，
in this case the output is on top,
在这种情况下，输出在顶部，
you encode
你编码
the video
该视频
into a representation inside the network
进入网络内部的表示
and then you start generating words
然后你开始生成单词
about that video.
关于那个视频。
First comes the input, the encoding stage,  then the decoding stage.
首先是输入，编码阶段，然后是解码阶段。
Take in the video,
接收视频，
say a man is taking,
说一个男人正在服用，
talking, whatever
说话，无论如何
and because the input and the output are arbitrary,
因为输入和输出是任意的，
there also has to be indicators of the beginnings and
还必须有开头的指标和
the ends of a sentence,
一句话的结尾，
in this case, end of sentences.
在这种情况下，句子结束。
You want to know when you stop
你想知道什么时候停下来
in order to generate syntactically correct sentences.
为了生成语法正确的句子。
that indicates the end of a sentence. You want also to be able to generate a period
表示句子结束。您还希望能够生成句点
You can also, again, recurrent neural networks,
您还可以再次使用递归神经网络，
LSTMs here,
LSTM在这里，
controlling
控制
the steering
转向
of a sliding window on an image
图像上的滑动窗口
that is used to classify what is contained in that image.
用于对该图像中包含的内容进行分类。
Here, a CNN being steered by a recurrent neural network
这里，CNN由循环神经网络操纵
in order to convert this imagen
为了转换这个图像
into the number that's associated with a house number,
到与门牌号码相关联的号码，
it's called visual attention.
它被称为视觉注意力。
That visual attention can be used to steer
视觉注意可以用来引导
for the perception side
对于感知方面
and it can be used to steer a network for the generation.
它可以用来引导网络进行生成。
On the right,
在右边，
we can generate an image as--
我们可以生成一个图像 -
So the output of the network--
所以网络的输出 -
it's a LSTM
这是一个LSTM
where the output on every time step
每个时间步的输出
is visual,
是视觉的，
and this way you can draw numbers.
这样你就可以绘制数字。
Here,
这里，
I mention this before,
我之前提过这个，
is taking in as input silent video,
正在输入无声视频，
sequence of images
图像序列
and producing audio.
并产生音频。
This is
这是
an LSTM
LSTM
that has convolutional layers for every single frame,
每个帧都有卷积层，
takes images as input
将图像作为输入
and produces
并生产
a spectrogram, audio as output.
频谱图，音频作为输出。
The training set is a person hitting an object with a drumstick
训练集是用鼓槌敲击物体的人
and your task is to generate, given a silent video,
你的任务是生成一个无声的视频，
generate the sound that the drumstick will make
产生鼓槌会发出的声音
when in contact with that object.
与该物体接触时。
Medical diagnosis,
医学诊断，
that's actually--
那实际上是 -
I've listed some places where it has been really successful
我已经列出了一些非常成功的地方
and pretty cool,
非常酷，
but it's also beginning to be applied
但它也开始应用
in places where
在哪里的地方
can actually
实际上可以
really help
真有帮助
civilization, in medical applications.
文明，在医疗应用中。
For medical diagnosis
用于医疗诊断
there's
有
the highly spars and
高度的桅杆和
variable lengths
可变长度
sequence of information in the form of,
形式的信息序列，
for example, patient electronic health records.
例如，患者电子健康记录。
So, Every time you visit a doctor,
所以，每次去看医生，
there's a test being done, that information is there
正在进行测试，信息就在那里
and you can look it as a sequence over a period of time
你可以把它看作一段时间的序列
and then given that data, that's the input,
然后给出数据，这是输入，
the output is the diagnosis,
输出是诊断，
a medical diagnosis,
医学诊断，
in this case, we can look at predicting diabetes,
在这种情况下，我们可以看看预测糖尿病，
scoliosis, asthma and\hso on,
脊柱侧凸，哮喘等，
with pretty good accuracy.
具有非常好的准确性。
There's something that
有一些东西
all of us wish we could do,
我们所有人都希望我们能做到，
is stock market prediction.
是股市预测。
You can input,
你可以输入，
for example, well first of all, you can input the raw stock data,
例如，首先，您可以输入原始库存数据，
[unintelligible 01:00:30] books and so on, financial data,
[难以理解的01:00:30]书籍等，财务数据，
but you can also look at news articles from all over the web
但您也可以查看来自网络的新闻报道
and take those as input as shown here,
并将这些作为输入，如此处所示，
on the X axis is time,
在X轴上是时间，
articles from different days,
来自不同日子的文章，
LSTM, once again,
LSTM，再一次，
and produce an output of your prediction,
并产生预测的输出，
binary prediction, whether the stock would go up or down.
二元预测，股票是上涨还是下跌。
Nobody has been able to really successfully do this
没有人能够真正成功地做到这一点
but there is a bunch of results
但是有很多结果
and trying to perform above random
并尝试随机执行
which is how you make money,
这是你赚钱的方式，
significantly above random
显着高于随机
on the prediction of it's going up or down?
在预测它上升或下降？
So you could buy or sell
所以你可以买卖
and especially
特别是
when there is--
当有 -
in the cases when there was crashes it's easier to predict,
在发生崩溃的情况下，更容易预测，
so you can predict an encroaching crash.
所以你可以预测一次闯入的崩溃。
These\hare shown in the table,
这些显示在表中，
the error rates from different stocks,
不同股票的错误率，
automotive stocks.
汽车股。
You can also generate audio,
你也可以生成音频，
is the exact same process as it generates language,
是与生成语言完全相同的过程，
you generate audio.
你生成音频。
Here's trained on
这是受过训练的
a single speaker,
一个扬声器，
a few hours epics
几个小时的史诗
of them speaking
他们说话
and you just learn, that's raw audio of the speaker
而你只是学习，这是扬声器的原始音频
and it's learning slowly to generate
它正在慢慢地学习生成
[audio]
[音频]
Obviously, they were reading numbers.
显然，他们正在阅读数字。
this is incredible, this is trained
这是不可思议的，这是训练有素的
on a compress spectrogram of the audio, raw audio
在音频，原始音频的压缩频谱图上
and is producing something that
并正在生产一些东西
over just a few epics is producing something that sounds like words,
只有少数史诗正在产生听起来像单词的东西，
it could do this lecture for me, I wish.
我希望它可以为我做这个讲座。
This is amazing,
这真太了不起了，
this is raw input,
这是原始输入，
raw output,
原始输出，
all again, LSTMs,
再一次，LSTMs，
and there's a lot of work in voice recognition,
在语音识别方面有很多工作，
audio recognition. You're mapping--
音频识别。你在映射 -
let me turn it up.
让我把它打开。
You are mapping any kind of audio to a classification,
您正在将任何类型的音频映射到分类，
you can take the audio of the road
你可以采取道路的音频
and that's the spectrogram on the bottom there, being shown
这是显示在底部的频谱图
you could detect whether the road is wet
你可以检测到道路是否潮湿
is wet or the road is dry.
潮湿或道路干燥。
you could do the same thing for
你可以做同样的事情
recognizing the gender of the speaker
认识到发言者的性别
or recognizing many to many map
或识别多对多的地图
of the actual words being spoken,
所说的实际单词，
speech recognition.
语音识别。
This is about driving,
这是关于驾驶，
so let's see where recurrent neural| networks apply in driving.
所以让我们看看复发神经的位置网络适​​用于驾驶。
We talked about the NVIDIA approach,
我们谈到了NVIDIA的方法，
the thing that actually powers DeepTeslaJS,
实际上是DeepTeslaJS的东西，
it is a simple convolutional neural network,
它是一个简单的卷积神经网络，
there's five convolutional layers
有五个卷积层
in their approach, three fully connected layers,
在他们的方法中，三个完全连接的层，
you can add as many layers as you want in DeepTesla,
您可以在DeepTesla中添加任意数量的图层，
that's a quarter of million
这是百万分之二
parameters to optimize
要优化的参数
all you are taking is a single image,
你要拍的只是一张图片，
no temporal information, single image
没有时间信息，单个图像
and producing the steering angle, that's the approach,
并产生转向角，这就是方法，
that's the DeepTesla way,
那是DeepTesla的方式，
taking a single imagen
拍摄一张照片
image and learning a regression of the steering angle.
图像和学习转向角的回归。
One of the
其中一个
prizes for the competition is the Udacity, self-driving
比赛的奖品是Udacity，自驾车
car engineer nanodegree
汽车工程师nanodegree
for free,
免费，
this thing is awesome,
这件事太棒了，
I encourage everyone to check it out,
我鼓励大家查看一下，
but they did a competition
但他们做了一场比赛
that's very similar to ours,
这跟我们的非常相似
but a very large group of obsessed people,
但是一大群痴迷者，
they were very clever, they went beyond
他们非常聪明，他们超越了
convolutional neural networks of predicting steering,
预测转向的卷积神经网络，
taking a sequence of images and predicting steering,
拍摄一系列图像并预测转向，
what they did is, the winners,
他们所做的是，获奖者，
at least the first and I'll talk about the second place winner tomorrow,
至少第一次，我将谈论明天的第二名，
on 3D convolutional neural networks,
在3D卷积神经网络上，
the first and the third place winners used RNNs,
第一名和第三名获奖者使用RNN，
used LSTMs, recurrent neural networks
使用LSTMs，循环神经网络
and map a sequence of images
并映射一系列图像
to a sequence of steering angles.
到一系列转向角。
For anyone,
对任何人，
statistically speaking,
从统计学上讲，
anybody here who is not a computer vision person,
这里的任何人都不是计算机视觉的人，
most likely what'd you want to use, for whatever application
对于任何应用程序，最有可能你想要使用什么
you're interested in,
你有兴趣，
is RNNs,
是RNN，
the world is full of time series data,
世界充满了时间序列数据，
very few of us are working on
我们很少有人在努力
data that is no time series data,
没有时间序列数据的数据，
in fact, whenever it's just snapshots,
事实上，只要它只是快照，
you're really just reducing the problem to
你真的只是把问题减少到了
the size that you can handle
你可以处理的大小
but most data
但大多数数据
in the world is time series data.
在世界上是时间序列数据。
This is the approach you end up using
这是您最终使用的方法
if you want to apply it in your own research,
如果你想在自己的研究中应用它，
RNNs is the way to go.
RNN是要走的路。
Again, what are they doing?
再一次，他们在做什么？
How do you put images
你怎么放图像
into a recurrent neural network?
进入一个递归的神经网络？
it's the same thing,
这是同一件事，
you take,
你拿，
you have to convert an image into numbers
你必须将图像转换为数字
in some kind of way,
以某种方式，
a powerful way of doing that is convolutional neural networks,
一种强有力的方法是卷积神经网络，
so you can take
所以你可以参加
either 3D convolutional neural networks
三维卷积神经网络
or 2D convolutional neural networks
或2D卷积神经网络
once it takes time into consideration and whatnot,
一旦需要时间考虑和诸如此类的，
process that image
处理那个图像
to extract a representation of that image
提取该图像的表示
and that becomes the input to the LSTM
这成为LSTM的输入
and the output
和输出
at every single cell, at every single timestep,
在每一个单元格，每一个时间步，
is a predicted steering angle,
是预测的转向角，
the speed of the vehicle and the torque
车辆的速度和扭矩
that's what the first place winner did,
这是第一名获胜者所做的，
they didn't just do the steering angle,
他们不只是做转向角，
also did the speed and torque
也做了速度和扭矩
and the sequence length that they were using
以及他们使用的序列长度
for training and for testing,
用于培训和测试，
for the input and the output,
对于输入和输出，
is a sequence length of 10\h
序列长度为10
did they used supervised learning
他们是否使用过监督学习
or did they used reinforcement learning?
或者他们是否使用过强化学习？
The question was, did they used supervised learning?
问题是，他们是否使用过监督学习？
Yes, they were given the same thing as in DeepTesla,
是的，他们被给予与DeepTesla相同的东西，
a sequence of frames where the have a sequence of
一系列帧，其序列为
steering angles, speed and torque,
转向角，速度和扭矩，
I think there's other information too available,
我认为还有其他信息，
there's no reinforcement learning here.
这里没有强化学习。
Question.\h
题。
Do you have a sense of how much information
你有多少信息感吗？
is being passed,\hhow many LSTM gates are there
正在通过，有多少LSTM门
in this problem?
在这个问题？
The question was,
问题是，
how many LSTM gates are\hin this problem?
这个问题有多少个LSTM门？
This network,
这个网络，
it's true
这是真的
that this diagrams kind of hide
这个图有点隐藏
the number of parameters here, but it's arbitrary
这里的参数数量，但它是任意的
just like convolutional neural networks are arbitrary,
就像卷积神经网络是任意的，
the size of the input is arbitrary,
输入的大小是任意的，
the size of Sigmoid function,
Sigmoid函数的大小，
TANH is arbitrary,
TANH是任意的，
so you can make it as large as you want, as deep as you want
所以你可以根据自己的需要尽可能大地制作它
and the deeper and larger, the better.\h
越深越好。
What these folks actually used--
这些人实际使用了什么 -
the way these competitions work
这些比赛的运作方式
and I encourage you, if you're interested in machine learning
如果你对机器学习感兴趣，我鼓励你
to participate in Kaggle,
参加Kaggle，
I don't know how to pronounce it, competitions
我不知道如何发音，比赛
where basically everyone is doing the same thing,
基本上每个人都在做同样的事情，
you're using LSTMs
你正在使用LSTM
or if it's one- on-one mapping,
或者如果它是一对一的映射，
using convolutional neural network fully connecting networks
使用卷积神经网络完全连接网络
with some clever pre-processing
有一些聪明的预处理
and the whole job is that takes months
整个工作需要几个月
and you probably, if you're a researcher,
你可能，如果你是研究员，
that's what you'd be doing your own research,
这就是你自己研究的内容，
playing with parameters,
玩参数，
playing with pre-processing of the data,
玩预处理数据，
playing with the different parameter that controls the size of the network
使用控制网络大小的不同参数
the learning rate,
学习率，
I've mentioned, this type of optimizer,
我已经提到过，这种类型的优化器，
all these kinds of things, that's what you're playing with,
所有这些东西，这就是你正在玩的东西，
using your own human intuition
用你自己的人类直觉
and you're using your--
而你正在使用你的 -
whatever probing you can do
无论你能做什么探测
in monitoring the performansce of the network
监控网络的性能
through time.
通过时间。
Yes?
是？
The question was,
问题是，
you said that there's a
你说有一个
memory of tenth in this LCM,
在这个LCM中记忆第十，
and I thought RNNs are supposed to be arbitrary.
我认为RNN应该是任意的。
It has to do
它必须这样做
with the training,
通过培训，
how the network is trained.
如何训练网络。
It's trained with sequences of 10.
它训练有10个序列。
The structure is still the same, you only have one
结构仍然相同，你只有一个
cell that's looping onto each other.
正在相互循环的细胞。
But the question is,
但问题是，
in what chunks,
在什么块，
what is the size of the sequence
序列的大小是多少
that we should do in the training and then the testing.
我们应该在培训和测试中做。
It can be arbitrary length.
它可以是任意长度。
It's just usually better to be consistent
保持一致通常更好
and have a fixed length.
并有一个固定的长度。
You're not stacking 10 cells together.
你没有将10个细胞堆叠在一起。
It's just a single cell still.
它只是一个单元格。
The third-place winner,
第三名获胜者，
Team Chauffeur,
司机小组，
used something called transfer learning
使用称为转移学习的东西
and it's something I don't think I mentioned
这是我认为我没有提到的事情
but it's kind of implied,
但它有点暗示，
the amazing power of neural networks.
神经网络的惊人力量。
First, you need a lot of data to do anything.
首先，您需要大量数据才能执行任何操作。
That's the cost, that's the limitation in neural networks.
这就是成本，这是神经网络的限制。
But what you could do is,
但你能做的是，
there's
有
neural networks that have been trained on very large data sets.
已经在非常大的数据集上训练的神经网络。
ImageNet,
ImageNet，
Vdg Net, AlexNet, ResNet,
Vdg Net，AlexNet，ResNet，
all these networks are trained on a huge amount of data.
所有这些网络都接受了大量数据的培训。
Those networks are trained to tell
这些网络经过培训可以讲述
the differences between a cat and dog Specific optical recognition
猫与狗之间的差异具体光学识别
of single images.
单个图像。
How do I then take that network
我如何接受该网络
and apply it to my problem,
并将其应用于我的问题，
say of driving or length detection,
说到驾驶或长度检测，
or medical diagnosis, or cancer or not?
或医学诊断，或癌症与否？
The beauty of neural networks,
神经网络之美，
the promise of transfer learning,
转学的承诺，
is that you can just take that network,
是你可以采取该网络，
chop off the final layer,
切掉最后一层，
the fully connected layer
完全连接的层
that maps from all those cool
那些很酷的地图
high-dimensional features that you have learned about visual space,
您从视觉空间中学到的高维特征，
and as opposed to predicting cat vs. dog,
而不是预测猫与狗，
you teach it to predict cancer or no cancer.
你教它预测癌症或没有癌症。
You teach it to predict lane or no lane, truck or no truck.
你教它预测车道或没有车道，卡车或没有卡车。
As long as the visual space
只要视觉空间
under which that network operates
该网络运作的基础
is similar or the data like if it's audio or whatever
是类似的或数据，如果它是音频或其他什么
if it's similar, if the features are useful then you learn,
如果它是相似的，如果功能有用，那么你学习，
in studying the problem of cat vs dog deeply,
深入研究猫与狗的问题，
you have learned actually how to see the world.
你实际上已经学会了如何看世界。
As you're going to apply that visual knowledge,
当你要应用那种视觉知识时，
you can transfer that learning
你可以转移那种学习
to another domain.
到另一个域。
That's the beautiful power of neural networks
这就是神经网络的美妙力量
it's that they're transferable.
这是他们可以转让的。
What they did here is--
他们在这里做的是 -
I didn't spend enough time looking through the code
我没有花足够的时间查看代码
I'm not sure which of the giant nework they took
我不确定他们采取了哪一个巨型的纽约
but they took a giant convolutional neural network,
但他们采用了巨大的卷积神经网络，
they chopped off
他们砍掉了
the end layer,
最后一层，
which produced 3000 features,
它产生了3000个功能，
and they took those 3000 features
他们采用了这3000个功能
to every single image frame,
到每一个图像帧，
and that's the Xt.
这就是Xt。
They gave that as the input to LSTM.
他们把它作为LSTM的输入。
And the sequence length, in that case, was 50.
在这种情况下，序列长度为50。
This process is pretty
这个过程非常好
similar across domains. That's the beauty of it.
跨域相似。这就是它的美丽。
The art of neural networks is in the--
神经网络的艺术在于 -
Well\hthat's a good sign
那是个好兆头
[chuckles],
[笑]
I guess I should warp it up--
我想我应该扭曲它 -
The art of the neural networks is in the proper parameter tuning.\h
神经网络的艺术在于适当的参数调整。
That's the tricky part,
这是棘手的部分，
and that's the part you can't be taught.
那是你无法教授的部分。
That's experience,
这是经验，
sadly enough.
可悲的是。
That's why they talk about
这就是他们谈论的原因
Stochastic Gradient Descent SGD,
随机梯度下降SGD，
That's what Geoffrey Hinton
那就是杰弗里·辛顿
refers to as
指的是
Stochastic Graduate Student Descent,
随机研究生后裔，
meaning you just keep hiring graduate students
意思是你只是招聘研究生
to play with the hyperparameters
使用超参数
until the problem is solved
直到问题解决了
[laughter].
[笑声]。
I have about
我有
100+ slides on driver state,
驱动程序状态下100多张幻灯片，
which is the thing that I'm most passionate about,
这是我最热衷的事情，
and I think will save the best for last.
而且我认为最后会拯救最好的。
I'll talk about that tomorrow. We have a guest speaker
我明天会谈到这个。我们有演讲嘉宾
from the White House,
来自白宫，
will talk about the future of Artificial Intelligence
将谈论人工智能的未来
from the perspective of policy,
从政策的角度来看，
and what I would like you to do first off you registered students is submit
我希望你先注册的是你注册的学生提交的内容
the two tutorial assignments,
两个教程作业，
and pick up
然后接
can we just set the boxes right here or something?
我们可以在这里设置盒子还是什么？
Just stop by and pick up a shirt.
只是停下来拿一件衬衫。
And give us a card on the way.
并在路上给我们一张卡片。
Thanks guys.
多谢你们。
[Applause]
[掌声]